Sure if you local realtor today, I wanted to go over if it's smarter to buy real estate or rent it
Let's do the numbers and find out let's do the numbers and figure it out
So when you're renting the average rent in the US is $1,700 per month
times
360 months because that's what usual mortgage would come out to you'd end up paying
$612,000 and hold no money in your pocket when you're buying something so the average price of a home is
$404,000 if you buy this home with 10% down at a 6% interest rate
Your monthly payment would come out to $2,750 over the whole term of your loan. You'd end up paying
$989,000 for the
$404,000 house you just bought but it should be worth
$980,000 after the term of your mortgage because the average appreciation per year is 3%
So if that $404,000 property goes up 3% every year after the 30 years, it should be worth
$980,000. So the renter spent
$612,000 within
360 months but had nothing to sell after so he did spend about
$300,000 less than the buyer but the buyer had something to sell for about a million dollars after that 30 years in
My opinion buying is definitely the smarter option for you because you'll have something to sell at least after
It is expensive, but it should be worth it financially
If you need help buying or selling your next property, give me a call at 917-951-2142